<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finland on quan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/series/finland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finland on quan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 23:29:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/series/finland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leave my 2 years job and moving to Finland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/lifestyle_in_finland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 23:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/lifestyle_in_finland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;./featured.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio/blog/lifestyle_in_finland/featured.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deciding to leave a stable job is never easy, especially when you&amp;rsquo;ve invested two years of your life into it. However, sometimes the call for change becomes too loud to ignore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my reality a few months ago when I decided to leave my job and relocate to Finland. Here’s why I made this life-changing decision and what I hope to achieve in my new chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;seeking-new-challenges&#34;&gt;Seeking New Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two years in my role, I found myself yearning for new challenges. The initial excitement had waned, and my professional growth felt stagnant. I believe that comfort can sometimes be the enemy of progress. Moving to Finland presented an opportunity to step out of my comfort zone and immerse myself in a new professional landscape. Finland&amp;rsquo;s burgeoning tech scene and innovative work culture were significant draws for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality-of-life&#34;&gt;Quality of Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finland consistently ranks high in global quality of life indices. Factors such as excellent healthcare, a robust social security system, and a focus on work-life balance make it an attractive place to live. The idea of living in a society that values well-being and sustainability resonated deeply with me. I wanted to experience a lifestyle where professional success and personal happiness go hand-in-hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education-and-professional-development&#34;&gt;Education and Professional Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finland is renowned for its education system. Even as a professional, there are numerous opportunities for continuous learning and development. The country encourages lifelong learning, and many employers support further education and professional development. I’m excited about the prospects of expanding my skill set and advancing my career in such a supportive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-experience&#34;&gt;Cultural Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in a new country offers a rich cultural experience. Finland’s unique blend of tradition and modernity, its stunning natural landscapes, and the famed Finnish way of life (including the love for saunas and respect for nature) are all aspects I’m eager to explore. Experiencing different cultures broadens one’s perspective and fosters personal growth. I look forward to embracing Finnish culture and making new connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-life-balance&#34;&gt;Work-Life Balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finnish work culture places a strong emphasis on work-life balance. Unlike the often relentless pace found in many other countries, Finnish companies typically encourage employees to take breaks and prioritize their well-being. This balance is crucial for maintaining mental and physical health, and it&amp;rsquo;s something I felt was lacking in my previous job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adventure-and-exploration&#34;&gt;Adventure and Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the move to Finland is an adventure. It’s about exploring a new part of the world, trying new things, and stepping into the unknown. Life is too short to stay in one place out of fear or convenience. Embracing this change is about living fully and making the most out of the opportunities life presents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving my job of two years was a difficult decision, but one that I believe is for the best. Moving to Finland is an exciting step toward new professional challenges, a better quality of life, and a chance to grow both personally and professionally. Change can be daunting, but it is also the catalyst for growth and new opportunities. Here’s to new beginnings in Finland!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>