<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on quan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 23:29:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Roadmap for studying AI Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/my_roadmap_in_ai_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 23:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/my_roadmap_in_ai_engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post outlines my roadmap for studying AI Engineering, detailing the steps I plan to take, the resources I intend to use, and the milestones I aim to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing industries across the globe, and I am eager to be part of this transformative journey. This blog post outlines my roadmap for studying AI Engineering, detailing the steps I plan to take, the resources I intend to use, and the milestones I aim to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-setting-clear-goals&#34;&gt;Step 1: Setting Clear Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;short-term-goals&#34;&gt;Short-Term Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand the Fundamentals&lt;/strong&gt;: Gain a strong foundation in mathematics, programming, and basic AI concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete Online Courses&lt;/strong&gt;: Enroll in and complete introductory AI courses on platforms like Coursera, edX, and Udacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build Simple Projects&lt;/strong&gt;: Apply what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned by working on small AI projects and experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-term-goals&#34;&gt;Long-Term Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earn a Degree&lt;/strong&gt;: Pursue a formal education in AI Engineering, either through a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s or master&amp;rsquo;s program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop Advanced Skills&lt;/strong&gt;: Specialize in areas such as machine learning, deep learning, and natural language processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribute to Open-Source Projects&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage with the AI community by contributing to open-source AI projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-acquiring-essential-knowledge&#34;&gt;Step 2: Acquiring Essential Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mathematics&#34;&gt;Mathematics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong grasp of mathematics is crucial for AI. I will focus on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Algebra&lt;/strong&gt;: Understanding vectors, matrices, and their applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calculus&lt;/strong&gt;: Learning about derivatives, integrals, and optimization techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probability and Statistics&lt;/strong&gt;: Grasping the concepts of probability distributions, statistical inference, and hypothesis testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;programming-skills&#34;&gt;Programming Skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proficiency in programming is a must for AI Engineering. My plan includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;: Mastering Python, the primary language used in AI development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Libraries and Frameworks&lt;/strong&gt;: Familiarizing myself with key libraries and frameworks like NumPy, pandas, TensorFlow, and PyTorch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-ai-concepts&#34;&gt;Basic AI Concepts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the core concepts of AI, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: Learning about supervised, unsupervised, and reinforcement learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neural Networks&lt;/strong&gt;: Exploring the architecture and functioning of neural networks and deep learning models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-enrolling-in-online-courses-and-certifications&#34;&gt;Step 3: Enrolling in Online Courses and Certifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-courses&#34;&gt;Recommended Courses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coursera&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning by Andrew Ng&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning Specialization by Andrew Ng and team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edX&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI for Everyone by Andrew Ng&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principles of Machine Learning by Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Udacity&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AI Programming with Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Reinforcement Learning Nanodegree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;certifications&#34;&gt;Certifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google AI&lt;/strong&gt;: Obtaining certifications such as TensorFlow Developer Certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft AI&lt;/strong&gt;: Earning certifications through Microsoft’s AI Engineer program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-4-practical-experience-through-projects&#34;&gt;Step 4: Practical Experience through Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-projects&#34;&gt;Building Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beginner Projects&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handwritten digit recognition using MNIST dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple chatbot using Natural Language Processing (NLP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermediate Projects&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image classification using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sentiment analysis on social media posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Projects&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implementing Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) for image generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing a recommendation system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contributing-to-open-source&#34;&gt;Contributing to Open-Source&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;: Contributing to AI projects and collaborating with other developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kaggle&lt;/strong&gt;: Participating in AI competitions and learning from the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-5-pursuing-formal-education&#34;&gt;Step 5: Pursuing Formal Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bachelors-or-masters-degree&#34;&gt;Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s or Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universities&lt;/strong&gt;: Applying to universities with strong AI programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courses&lt;/strong&gt;: Focusing on AI-specific courses and electives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research&lt;/strong&gt;: Engaging in AI research projects and internships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-6-joining-ai-communities-and-networks&#34;&gt;Step 6: Joining AI Communities and Networks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-communities&#34;&gt;Online Communities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reddit&lt;/strong&gt;: Joining subreddits like r/MachineLearning and r/ArtificialIntelligence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/strong&gt;: Participating in discussions and seeking advice from experienced AI engineers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;professional-networks&#34;&gt;Professional Networks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/strong&gt;: Connecting with AI professionals and following AI-related companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meetups and Conferences&lt;/strong&gt;: Attending AI conferences, webinars, and local meetups to stay updated with the latest trends and network with peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey to becoming an AI Engineer is challenging but incredibly rewarding. By setting clear goals, acquiring essential knowledge, gaining practical experience, pursuing formal education, and joining AI communities, I am confident in my ability to succeed in this exciting field. I look forward to sharing my progress and insights as I embark on this roadmap to studying AI Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leave my 2 years job and moving to Finland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/lifestyle_in_finland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 23:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/blog/lifestyle_in_finland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;./featured.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/portfolio/portfolio/blog/lifestyle_in_finland/featured.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deciding to leave a stable job is never easy, especially when you&amp;rsquo;ve invested two years of your life into it. However, sometimes the call for change becomes too loud to ignore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my reality a few months ago when I decided to leave my job and relocate to Finland. Here’s why I made this life-changing decision and what I hope to achieve in my new chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;seeking-new-challenges&#34;&gt;Seeking New Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two years in my role, I found myself yearning for new challenges. The initial excitement had waned, and my professional growth felt stagnant. I believe that comfort can sometimes be the enemy of progress. Moving to Finland presented an opportunity to step out of my comfort zone and immerse myself in a new professional landscape. Finland&amp;rsquo;s burgeoning tech scene and innovative work culture were significant draws for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality-of-life&#34;&gt;Quality of Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finland consistently ranks high in global quality of life indices. Factors such as excellent healthcare, a robust social security system, and a focus on work-life balance make it an attractive place to live. The idea of living in a society that values well-being and sustainability resonated deeply with me. I wanted to experience a lifestyle where professional success and personal happiness go hand-in-hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education-and-professional-development&#34;&gt;Education and Professional Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finland is renowned for its education system. Even as a professional, there are numerous opportunities for continuous learning and development. The country encourages lifelong learning, and many employers support further education and professional development. I’m excited about the prospects of expanding my skill set and advancing my career in such a supportive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultural-experience&#34;&gt;Cultural Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in a new country offers a rich cultural experience. Finland’s unique blend of tradition and modernity, its stunning natural landscapes, and the famed Finnish way of life (including the love for saunas and respect for nature) are all aspects I’m eager to explore. Experiencing different cultures broadens one’s perspective and fosters personal growth. I look forward to embracing Finnish culture and making new connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-life-balance&#34;&gt;Work-Life Balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finnish work culture places a strong emphasis on work-life balance. Unlike the often relentless pace found in many other countries, Finnish companies typically encourage employees to take breaks and prioritize their well-being. This balance is crucial for maintaining mental and physical health, and it&amp;rsquo;s something I felt was lacking in my previous job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adventure-and-exploration&#34;&gt;Adventure and Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the move to Finland is an adventure. It’s about exploring a new part of the world, trying new things, and stepping into the unknown. Life is too short to stay in one place out of fear or convenience. Embracing this change is about living fully and making the most out of the opportunities life presents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving my job of two years was a difficult decision, but one that I believe is for the best. Moving to Finland is an exciting step toward new professional challenges, a better quality of life, and a chance to grow both personally and professionally. Change can be daunting, but it is also the catalyst for growth and new opportunities. Here’s to new beginnings in Finland!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>